welcome to meditating with Chandra Reiki
we livestream this meditation class
every weekday mornings at 9:30 a.m.
Eastern Time with Monday's alternating
between a lesson
Adama day for a review of the whole
ecology practices papaya day yesterday
was required if you're joining us for
the first time welcome for previous
lessons and sits please see the
description and you can go to the links
there
I recommend what you do is you do the
first lesson and then start joining us
every day and then do a new lesson a new
lesson buy out the recorded videos every
Saturday or Sunday then you can all do
to help me to reach as many people as
possible is to like this video stream to
completely increase its visibility on
the YouTube algorithm at the end of each
session we have QA please limit your
questions to questions about this course
the psychology of practices we are done
yet introductory course or removing into
more advanced techniques but you are
welcome to ask questions all the way
back to the very first lesson for more
encompassing questions about how to
situate this ecology practices within a
broader philosophy or way of life please
bring those questions to the live stream
Q&A that I do on YouTube every third
Friday of the month 3:00 p.m. Eastern
Time and that will be this Friday June
19th so I think that's all we need for
our our opening announcements so please
get your self into position please set
your phones on do not disturb and we
will begin when I say begin begin
[Music]
slowly commodity practice trying as best
you can to integrate what you cultivated
in your practice with your everyday
consciousness cognition the character
and communitas perhaps by reciting the
five promises to yourself
all right so yesterday we got cut off
towards the very end I was answering the
last question I just begun to answer it
I was cut off so I'd like to address
that question now from Kelly Meyers
welcome Kelly Kelly says I new to the
singer very welcome I hope you feel
welcome and I hope you feel this course
and the Sangha are affording you growth
in wisdom and new to this Sangha and
have been working through your first
lessons as well what shall I do with my
eyes turn the standing exercise open
close looking at looking through so very
much this is a very important question
is very important to keep your eyes open
and so when you are doing the standing
practices when you're doing the book you
know each one and the tenth run it's
important to you have what are called
Tiger eyes so the tiger is a symbol in
Taoism because the the tiger represents
there's optimal relationship between
flexibility and force awareness but the
ability to be still and silent and so
Tiger eyes means exactly that that your
eyes are moving and within it so it's
not a sort of dull contentedness and
it's not a hard fixation on anything
it's very much a flowing soft vigilance
that's especially when we're doing the
the yin-yang exercise it flows out and
it flows in it goes out in awe for
example to the circumference and then it
flows in and witness towards the
grounding in the center for the ah so
you're you you want your vision your
eyes to be open and you want to have
flowing flexible but there's it's it's
there's force in the sense of like where
the tiger has that graceful aliveness
that light from a Tiger Tiger burning
bright in the forests of the night right
so you want that
of vision and the idea is and that's why
we use the term the idea is that
perceptual vision if you properly
practice it in this imaginal fashion not
imaginary imaginal function actually
trains vision in the sense of virtue and
the mental psychological virtuous sense
of vision like when the bible says
without a vision the people perish right
so you that's what you're doing your
training
Tiger eyes perceptual vision so that you
actually afford the training of the
virtue of vision so I hope that answers
your question us cipriani
you're still looking for the space
between your thoughts maybe try to the
quiet between the voices yes yes
excellent excellent excellent I should
have said that thank you for saying that
yes very much
you also ought to listen for the quiet
between the voices and you want to know
you want to again since that's that
silence as the energetic Living
potential for those voices that they
actually emerged out of it are
constantly living from it yes excellent
well done that's very good
Chris Trafford I've run out of
indifference and different people in my
meta practice and it's getting boring
using the same people suggestions use
other people use other people and if you
can't use other people then try a
practice I believe it was a few lessons
ago where I was answering a question
about meta I'll come to both this you
can try the view from above which
doesn't require you to remember specific
people all Alaska Martu I look for the
link to that lesson and we'll put it in
the description this video soon and I'm
going to come back to that when we do
the wisdom of parnisha
you can try the view from above and
when you as a way of getting the same
kind of reciprocal opening you get it no
matter and then when you're at the
highest level of the youth or above then
you can direct met at words all beings
or even towards being itself so you can
try that Chris but you can also just
more prosaically try different people if
that's helpful to you to also not very
good at visualization so finding the box
person my thoughts difficult to see any
other methods
so when you say visualization not does
that also mean that I know that there's
about five percent of the population
that it does not really have sort of
explicit visual imagery in non Dreaming
States and so you may be one of those
people and so I understand the challenge
now there's quite a bit of variation so
I and I don't know you so one of the
questions I would ask is right when you
don't have the boss cars between a
thought but the is just excellent
question
do you have noises do your voices can
you listen for the silence between the
voices so if it's if you've got good
auditory imagery rather the visual
imagery can you shift the metaphor
instead of looking for the space
listening for the silence or if that
doesn't work feel for the stillness your
mind is moving you have some sense of
your mind moving can you get the can you
also become aware of feeling when your
mind is still even when your mind is
still taupey kohonen how do I make sure
I'm not taking spiritual development
into having mode inflating yeah so
that's really good question and the the
way to ask this is how if asked this
question really really deeply and what I
mean by that is don't ask it just of us
or in the practice because every
practice has its dangers and its risks
that's why I was taught I believe and
why I'm teaching you an ecology of
practices and one of the things and even
this ecology has to be set into a more
encompassing ecology of practices and
that's so that oh how is this
translating into your life
I wasn't translating into other product
is that you do I recommend having a
regular self-examination practice drawn
from stoicism at the end of everyday
writing in a journal try to reflect on
my moments of mindfulness moments of
wisdom moments we missed those
opportunities moments where you fell
prey to self-deception moments where you
realize upon reflection you realized
that you're a very sort of self
referential self-centered rather than
reality centered overcoming
self-centeredness does not mean self the
self abasement it's it's but that's why
the the the middle path is neither self
abasement in asceticism nor self
centeredness in self indulgent the
middle path is to be reality centric
rather than self centric and so you
thinking oh well the alternative to self
centeredness is i'm going to be a
doormat that's still locked within the
that whole way of thinking and so ask
yourself when you're when you're
reminded of your practice throughout the
day and in your uncle's with each other
what what comes up for you are you
remembering it as something that is in
any way self aggrandizing that is
feeling narcissism that is making you
want to feel special or unique right or
or perhaps the other that when your
spiritual comes up it's it reflects you
know that the way you dislike yourself
or hate yourself or are you noting that
because of your spiritual practice
you're getting more of those moments
when where you're zeroing in on what's
relevant and real in a situation
relevant and real and other people
especially are noticing that you can
zero in on what's relevant and real if
your your look to the encompassing your
encompassing frame of life to see what
how are the seeds of your practice
coming to fruition and that's how you
judge what's happening in your practice
so excellent questions very very
excellent questions so thank you very
much for them and for this nourishing
Sangha thank you all for joining as
always I want to thank my dear friend
and techni major Mar that makes
everything happen right my beloved son
Jason who's always behind the scenes
especially on Dharma day
and you PI a day moving the cameras
around on helping me out closing windows
adjusting things very grateful for that
please subscribe to this channel to be
notified of the next video you'll also
find on their links to the lecture
series awakening from the meaning crisis
and to the dialogue the logo series
voices with reveille key where these
themes are explored more in depth and
situated into a more encompassing
framework that I was just like look what
I was just talking about and find others
who might benefit by sharing this series
please Brett is here pleasure of the
doubt go on to the discord server there
will be a link in the description to
this video where you'll find people who
have just done this sitting or might
take it into Lexi Oh Davina might take
it into Lexi to do logos and then just a
broader and richer community of
discussion that's going on I meet I'm
there every second Monday night at 6
p.m. Eastern time for QA and many of the
people that I do that I have to get into
dialogue with on voices with verve a key
evander clay Andrew Kelly and layman
Pascal and I said stock there they also
go on there for Q&A it's very rich and
vibrant and vital community a reminder
that we do this practice every weekday
morning at 9:30 Eastern Time please
remember that continuity of practice is
more important than quantity of practice
there is no enemy worse than your own
mind and body no Ally no friend no true
true companion on the path better than
your own mind and body
he laughs unto yourself and to each
other I'll see you tomorrow
take good care